In this cell, I've split our features and
我在此单元格中将特征和编码标签
encoded labels into training test and validation sets.
拆分成了训练集、测试集和验证集
I started by splitting our features and label data according to their split frac.
首先根据 split_frac 拆分特征和标签数据
So, I'm reserving 80 percent of my data for
将 80% 的数据用于训练
training and I'm basically getting the index at which I should split
我根据 0.8 这个值
my features and label data based on this value
判断在哪个索引处拆分特征和标签数据
0.8 and actually I could have just put in this variable here.
我可以直接把这个变量放在这里
Then I'm splitting my features first,
先拆分特征
getting the features up until my 80 percent split index.
保留直到 80% 拆分索引处的所有特征
This makes up my training features train_x then I'm getting the remaining data.
这样就会获得训练特征 train_x 然后获取剩余数据
So, after the split index and that makes up my remaining_x.
即拆分索引之后的数据 并构成 remaining_x
Then, I'm doing the exact same thing but for my labels data,
然后对标签数据执行完全一样的操作
splitting it at the 80 percent index to get my training labels and
在 80% 索引处拆分标签
my remaining data then I'm doing something
获得训练标签及剩余数据
similar all over again only with the remaining data.
接着对剩余数据执行相似的操作
I'm getting an index to split this data in half,
需要将数据一分为二
so at the 0.5 mark.
所以拆分比例为 0.5
Then each half of our remaining_x will make up our validation and test sets of
remaining_x 的每一半将构成验证集和测试集特征
features and each half of remaining_y will make up our validation and test set of labels.
remaining_y 的每一半将构成验证集和测试集标签
That's it. The last step I'm doing is checking
搞定最后一步是检查代码
my work and printing out the shapes of my features data.
并输出特征数据的形状
I can see that I have the largest number of reviews in my training set with
可以看出训练集中有数量最多的影评
a sequence length of 200 and my validation and test sets are of the same size.
序列长度为 200 验证集和测试集的大小一样
If you want, you can do the same thing for
你可以输出标签数据的形状
your labels data and you should see the same number of rows here.
并且会在这里看到相同的行数
So, this is 80 percent of my data,
这是 80% 的数据
10 percent, and 10 percent.
这是 10% 这也是10%
After creating training test and validation data,
创建训练集、测试集和验证集之后
we want to batch this data so that we can train on batches at a time.
我们需要批处理数据 这样就能一次训练一批数据
Typically, you've seen this done with
之前我们一直都是使用生成器函数
a generator function which we could definitely do here but I want to show
现在还可以使用生成器函数
you a really nice way to batch our datasets when we've
但是我想要演示一种在拆分输入特征和标签时
split up our input features and labels like this.
批处理数据的很方便方式
We can actually create data loaders for our data by following a couple of steps.
我们可以创建数据加载器
First, we can use pytorch's tensor dataset to wrap
首先使用 PyTorch 的 TensorDataset
tensor data into a known format and I can look at the documentation for this here.
将数据封装为已知格式 我们看看 TensorDataset 的文档
This dataset basically takes any amount of tensors with the same first dimension,
该数据集会接受任意数量的张量
so the same number of rows,
并且第一个维度相同 即相同的行数
and in our case this is our input features and the label tensors and it
也就是我们的输入特征和标签张量
creates a dataset that can be processed and batched by pytorch's data loader class.
它会创建一个能被 PyTorch 的 DataLoader 类处理的数据
So, once we create our data wrapping it in a tensor dataset,
创建数据并将数据封装到 TensorDataset 里后
we can then pass that to a data loader as usual.
我们可以将其传递给 DataLoader
Data loader just takes in some data and
DataLoader 的参数包括一些数据和批次大小
a batch size and it returns a data loader that batches our data as we typically might.
返回一个对数据进行批处理的数据加载器
This is a great alternative to creating
这是一种创建生成器函数
a generator function for batching our data into full batches.
并将数据分成多个批次的很好方式
The data loader class is going to take care of a lot of
DataLoader 类将在后台为我们处理很多工作
behind-the-scenes work for us and here's what this looks like in code.
代码看起来是这样的
First, I'm creating my tensor datasets.
首先创建 TensorDataset
To create my training data,
要创建训练数据
I'm passing in the tensor version of my train_x and train_y that I created
在这里传入在上面创建的 train_x 和 train_y 的张量版本
above and torch that from numpy just
torch.from.numpy 会接受 NumPy 数组
takes in numpy arrays and converts them into tensors.
并将它们转换为张量
So, I'm doing that for my training validation and test
对训练、验证和测试数据执行相同的操作
data and if you named your data differently above,
如果你在上面为这些数据集设定了不同的名称
you'll have to change those names here.
则需要在这里使用这些名称
In fact, I could have actually done these steps the other way around.
也可以反过来执行这些操作
Creating a tensor dataset for all my data
先为所有数据创建一个张量数据集
and then splitting the data into different sets. Both approaches work.
然后将数据拆分为不同的数据集两种方法都可行
Then for each tensor dataset that I just created,
然后将刚刚创建的每个张量数据集
I'm passing it into pytorch's data loader or I can
传入 PyTorch 的 DataLoader 中
specify a batch size parameter equal to 50 in this case.
将 batch_size 设为 50
So, without the messiness of loops and yield commands,
我们不用使用各种循环和 yield 命令
this defines training validation and test data loaders
就能定义训练、验证和测试数据加载器
that I can use in my train loop to batch data into the size I want.
并在训练循环里使用这些加载器将数据批处理为指定大小
So, this gives me three different iterators and I just want to show you what a sample of
在这里生成了三个不同的迭代器
data from this data loader looks like
我们看看这个数据集加载器中的样本数据
looking at our train loader and getting an iterator,
在这里传入 train_loader 并获得一个迭代器
then grabbing one batch of data using a call to next.
然后通过调用 next() 获得一批数据
So, this should return some sample input features and some sample labels.
返回一些样本输入特征和样本标签
Then I'm printing out the size of my input which I can see is the batch size 50
然后输出输入数据的大小 结果显示批次大小为 50
and the sequence length 200 and the output label size which is just 50,
序列长度为 200 并且输出标签大小为 50
one label for each review in
输入批次数据中的每个影评对应一个标签
the input batch and I see my tokens and the encoded labels as well.
还有一些标记和编码标签
So, this is looking really great.
看起来没问题
Next, we can proceed with defining and training the model on this data.
接下来我们将继续定义模型并用这些数据训练模型